Finding Aid for the Walter R. Pope Collection
Special Collections Manuscripts and Rare Books
Walter R. Pope Collection
1918-1960
Special Collections Manuscripts and Rare Books
MSS.0340
.42 linear_feet
Scope and Contents
This .42 linear foot collection in 34 file folders contains various memorabilia of Walter R. Pope. It consists of biographical sketches, political campaign literature for the Republican Party (both national and local), military maps and reports, political newsletters, and letters. The collection is arranged by subject, in acid-free file folders, and housed in a manuscript box.
- The Majestic Atlas of the World
- Biographical Sketch - Portrait of a Chancellor – Dr. B. Harvie Branscomb Reprinted from the Nashville Tennessean Magazine, 1946 September 29
- Biographical Sketch - A Great Teacher’s Legacy – Edwin Mims
- Bulletin - Cumberland University, Lebanon, Tennessee, 1922 May
- Bulletin - Tennessee State Teachers’ Association
- Correspondence - Incoming
  - Successful Farming Magazine [Subscription renewal information w/inserts], March 1927
  - Successful Farming Magazine [Subscription renewal information w/inserts], March 1927
  - Ed Ingle, Republication National Committee, November 3, 1947
  - Arthur Rogers, June 10, 1948
  - Robert I. Taylor, Jr., March 1950
  - Guy L. Smith [telegram], November 6, 1952
- Diagnostic Tests
  - by Garry Cleveland Myers, Cleveland School of Education, 1925
    Math: addition, multiplication, division, subtraction, decimals, reading and writing numbers, division with remainders, and multiplication with carrying.
    English: verb demons, drill in every day verbs, easy synonyms, easy opposites, teaching word opposites, word studies, teaching synonyms, homonyms, and making sentences from mixed order words.
- Election Campaigns - National
  - Thomas E. Dewey, 1948
  - Harold E. Stassen, 1948
  - Dwight Eisenhower and Richard Nixon, 1952
- Election Campaigns - Local
  - Republican County Executive Committee [Weakley County], 1932-1934
  - Tennessee Governor’s Race – Republication Brochure, November 5, 1946
  - Official Ballott – General Election – Weakley County, August 2, 1951
  - Miscellaneous – (5) items
- Hearings
  - Subcommittee of the Committee on Post Offices, Part 1 & 2, 1929
- Magazine
  - The Republican, November 1944
    [The National Party Magazine]
- Military Maps
  - Giant War Map of the World, n.d. – (1)
  - Military occupation maps – newspaper clippings – (8)
- Military Report
  - Reorganization of the Army, January 28, 1920
- Newsletters
  - Battle Line (volume 1, number 1), August 24, 1960
    [An Official Publication of the Republican National Committee]
  - Battle Line (volume 1, number 2), September 19, 1960
  - National Republication Roundup Committee, 1950
- Pamphlets
  - Election Laws of the State of Tennessee, 1951
  - Great American Inventions, n.d.
  - Mesopotamia: The Key to the Future by Canon Parfit, n.d.
  - A Tale of Soap & Water by Grace T. Hallock, 1947
  - The Written Law by A. Thomas Thetford, 1944
  - This is the Hut the “Y” Built United War Work Campaign, November 1918
- Remarks
  - Hon. Hadwen C. Fuller of New York in the House of Representatives, October 2, 1945